<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="_c74_vig.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<vignette name="Building Collectives and Applications with TapTools">

	<bodytext>
		<img src="74objects-logo128.png" />
		<header1>Building Collectives and Applications with TapTools</header1>


		<sidebartext>
			<header2>Introduction</header2>
			<body>
				<ul>
				<!--	<li>Introduction</li>
					<li><link type="tutorial" module="max" name="maxindex">Tutorials</link></li> -->
					<li><link type="vignette" module="core" name="taptools_intro">TapTools Topics</link></li>
					<li><link type="vignette" module="core" name="taptools_authorization">Authorization</link></li>
					<!--	<li><link type="vignette" module="intro" name="taptools_software_update">Software Update</link></li> -->
					<li><link type="vignette" module="core" name="taptools_whats_new">What's New</link></li>
					<li><link type="vignette" module="core" name="taptools_support">Support</link></li>
				<!--	<li><link type="vignette" module="core" name="shortcuts">Tips and Shortcuts</link></li>
					<li><link type="vignette" module="core" name="messages_to_max">Messages to <o>max</o></link></li>
				-->
				</ul>
			</body>

			<header2>In Depth</header2>
			<body>
				<ul>
					<!--
					<li><link type="tutorial" module="msp" name="mspindex">Tutorials</link></li>
					<li><link type="tutorial" module="msp" name="mspintro">MSP Introduction</link></li>
					<li><link type="tutorial" module="msp" name="mspdigitalaudio">How Digital Audio Works</link></li>
					<li><link type="tutorial" module="msp" name="msphowmspworks">How MSP Works</link></li>
					<li><link type="tutorial" module="msp" name="mspaudioio">Audio I/O</link></li>
					<li><link type="vignette" module="core" name="msp_functional">MSP Objects by Function</link></li>
					<li><link type="vignette" module="core" name="msp_alphabetical">MSP Objects A-Z</link></li>
					<li><link type="vignette" module="core" name="messages_to_dsp">Messages to <o>dsp</o></link></li>
				-->
					<li><link type="vignette" module="core" name="taptools_and_collectives">Collectives &amp; Standalones</link></li>
				</ul>
			</body>
		</sidebartext>


		<header2>Understanding Collectives and Standalones</header2>
		<body>
			Collectives in Max are a special kind of file that bundle together many different files into a single document that you can distribute to others using Max. In addition to creating a collective, Max allows you to create standalone applications. Standalones bundle together a collective and the Max runtime so that you can distribute your work without any additional dependencies. 
			<br/><br/>
			
			TapTools consists of a number of files that are required to function properly. If you distribute your work using a simple collective, the user will need to have TapTools installed in order to use it. This is usually not ideal. For that reason it is recommended that you distribute your work as a standalone application. 
			<br /><br />
		</body>
			
		<header2>Building an Application</header2>
		<body>
			For details on building standalone applications in Max, first be sure to familiarize your self with Max's documentation on the subject. 

			The patcher that you compile into a standlone must contain an instance of the <o>standalone</o> object. This object must have the "extensions" option enabled. As of TapTools 3.1 that is all that you need, as TapTools Builder is now fully automatic.
		</body>
			
		<header2>Adding Additional Files to the Collective</header2>
		<body>
			TapTools includes an object to help with automating the process of building collectives, applications, and 
			plug-ins.  This object is called <o>tap.buildassist</o>.  The tap.buildassist object will add the specified
			file or folder to the collective when the patcher containing the object is built into one of the collective
			formats.  This obviates the need to create custom scripts for the collective builder.
			<br/><br/>
		</body>
			
		<header2>Licensing</header2>
		<body>
			To build collectives or standalones using TapTools, you must have your copy of TapTools authorized with
			a TapTools Pro license.  If you are using a TapTools Demo, TapTools Artist, or TapTools Student license
			then the collective or standalone application will not function properly after you build it.
			<br/><br/>
			
			Provided that you have a registered copy of TapTools Pro, no additional royalties or licensing restrictions are
			placed on your use of TapTools in the applications you build: free, commercial, or otherwise.
		</body>

	</bodytext>
</vignette>
