<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./_c74_ref.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<c74object name="tap.colorspace" module="max" category="TapTools, Math, Interface">

	<digest>
		Convert between colorspaces
	</digest>

	<description>
		These conversion routines were taken from Luke Dubois' Percolate Nato externals. His comments follow:
		<br/><br/>
		
		<blockquote>
			242.colorspace -- does colorspace conversion on an input image. by r. luke dubois (luke@music.columbia.edu), 
			computer music center, columbia university, 2001.
			<br/><br/>
		
			Most of the color conversion routines in this software are taken from rafael santos' color image processing toolkit. 
			The copyright below cites the original author. 
			Objects and source are provided without warranty of any kind, express or implied. 
			<br/><br/>
			
			Copyright (C) 1996, Rafael Santos. 
			Developed at the Ejima Lab / Department of Artificial Intelligence, Kyushu Institute of Technology.
			<br/><br/>
		</blockquote>
		
		For a thorough unit conversion utility, take a look at the <o>jcom.dataspace</o> object in <a href="http://jamoma.org">Jamoma</a>.
	</description>

	
	<!--METADATA-->
	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name="author">74 Objects</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">TapTools</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">Color</metadata>
	</metadatalist>

	
	<!--MESSAGES-->
	<methodlist>
		<method name="bang">
			<arglist/>
			<description>Calculate the conversion and output it from the object.</description>
		</method>
		<method name="int">
			<arglist>
				<arg name="input" type="int" optional="0" id="0" />
			</arglist>
			<description>Set one component of the input colorspace, and possible trigger output.</description>
		</method>
		<method name="float">
			<arglist>
				<arg name="input" type="float" optional="0" id="0" />
			</arglist>
			<description>Set one component of the input colorspace, and possible trigger output.</description>
		</method>
		<method name="list">
			<arglist>
				<arg name="input1" type="float" optional="0" id="0" />
				<arg name="input2" type="float" optional="0" id="0" />
				<arg name="input3" type="float" optional="0" id="0" />
			</arglist>
			<description>A list of the component values for the input colorspace, 
				which will be converted to the output colorspace.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methodlist>
	
	
	<!--ATTRIBUTES-->
	<attributelist>

		<attribute name="mode" get="1" set="1" type="symbol" size="1">
			<description>The mode determines which type of conversion will be done.  The available options are:
				no_transform, rgb2cmy, cmy2rgb, rgb2hsv, hsv2rgb, rgb2xyz, xyz2rgb, rgb2uvw, uvw2rgb, rgb2retinalcone, retinalcone2rgb, rgb2lab, lab2rgb, rgb2yiq, yiq2rgb, rgb2hls, hls2rgb, rgb2rgbcie, rgbcie2rgb, rgb2rgbsmpte, rgbsmpte2rgb, rgb2hsl, hsl2rgb.
				</description>
		</attribute>

		<attribute name="outputtype" get="1" set="1" type="symbol" size="1">
			<description>This symbol defines whether the output is sent as a list out of the first outlet, or individual components out of separate outlets.</description>
		</attribute>

		<attribute name="autopack" get="1" set="1" type="int" size="1">
			<description>
				When set to 1 tap.colorspace will send output every time one of the input components changes.
				Otherwise it will only trigger output when the left inlet changes.
			</description>
		</attribute>

	</attributelist>
	
	
	<!--SEEALSO-->
	<seealsolist>
		<seealso name="jit.colorspace"/>
	</seealsolist>

	
</c74object>
