<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' standalone='yes'?>


<!-- DO NOT EDIT THIS FILE ... YOU WILL LOSE YOUR WORK -->


<c74object name='tap.sustain~' category='buffer'>

	<digest>Capture recent audio into seamless sustaining loops</digest>
	<description>Continuously records its signal input. On a bang the most recently recorded material is captured into a voice, trimmed to significant-power zero-crossings at both ends, and played back as a crossfaded forward/backward loop so it sustains without clicks. A bank of voices is allocated round-robin so successive bangs stack overlapping loops, each rising in over the rise time. </description>


	<!--METADATA-->

	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name='author'>Timothy Place </metadata>
		<metadata name='tag'>buffer</metadata>
	</metadatalist>


	<!--ARGUMENTS-->

	<objarglist>

	</objarglist>


	<!--MESSAGES-->

	<methodlist>

		<method name='clear'>
			<digest>Erase all captured loops</digest>
			<description>Erase all captured loops (every voice) and reset the round-robin allocation cursor. </description>
		</method>

		<method name='bang'>
			<digest>Capture a sustaining loop</digest>
			<description>Capture the most recently recorded audio into a sustaining loop, allocated into the next voice round-robin so it overlaps any voices already sounding. </description>
		</method>

	</methodlist>


	<!--ATTRIBUTES-->

	<attributelist>

		<attribute name='fade' get='1' set='1' type='float64' size='1' >
			<digest>Length of crossfade across loop-points in milliseconds</digest>
			<description>Length of crossfade across loop-points in milliseconds. </description>
		</attribute>

		<attribute name='length' get='1' set='1' type='float64' size='1' >
			<digest>Maximum length of the captured loop in milliseconds</digest>
			<description>Maximum length of the captured loop in milliseconds. Changing this restarts the recording buffer. </description>
		</attribute>

		<attribute name='rise' get='1' set='1' type='float64' size='1' >
			<digest>Per-voice fade-in time in milliseconds</digest>
			<description>Time over which each newly captured voice grows to full power, in milliseconds. Applied independently per voice as a one-shot fade-in when it starts sustaining, so a stacked voice swells in under the others rather than clicking in. </description>
		</attribute>

		<attribute name='voices' get='1' set='1' type='int' size='1' >
			<digest>Number of overlapping sustaining voices</digest>
			<description>Number of overlapping sustaining voices (1-5, default 5). Each bang captures into the next voice round-robin, so up to this many loops can stack before the oldest is recycled. </description>
		</attribute>

	</attributelist>


	<!--RELATED-->

	<seealsolist>
		<seealso name='buffer~' />
		<seealso name='record~' />
		<seealso name='tap.buffer.record~' />
	</seealsolist>


</c74object>
